It's not sunny outside today.
>> No, it's a long ride home. So,
>> you can stay in my basement
to get on the course.
Why do you guys turn your phones over?
You don't want us to see who's calling
or text like what?
>> Just curious.
>> Yeah.
>> You never know.
>> We're out.
>> We're done.
>> Some of your friends left, S though.
There's not They're not all here from
yesterday.
>> Um ready for the game.
>> Kind of take us through the early part
of the day. uh with what you did there
uh the first trade of the day and then
just how you addressed it. You had key
needs at linebacker. We talked about it
as a wide receiver that about the early
>> Yeah. Uh we started with Jude um the
tackle, you know, losing Vandermark this
year. Um played a big role for us as as
a swing guy last year. Uh obviously lost
him as a you know, restricted free
agent. So, um, tackle's a premium
position and, you know, we were
following some guys even yesterday, but,
you know, Jude was, you know, the best
player on our board at the time and he
he filled, you know, a need, you know,
that yesterday we weren't able to do.
And, you know, he's going to come in
here and compete. The good thing about
Judy's not just a tackle, we do uh,
believe he can come inside and compete
at the guard position. So, we like his
versatility. Where do you think he'll
start in terms of those two?
>> Yeah, I would say we'll just start him
at swing tackle, but but mix them in. We
like to, you know, the versatility of it
at all. Just, you know, like Greyel's
done that in his time here as well.
>> Uh, who else do you want me to talk
about? The
>> You had too, right? Was he
um the receiver?
>> Yeah.
>> Yes, we had Elim or
>> We had you guys working a lot today,
huh?
>> Yeah. So, Bell was next. Um really like
Bell a lot, you know. Um Joe and I sat
down with Pete and Drew Terrell u you
know few days before the draft and just
looked at certain players, talked about
their fit. He was one that we kind of
extensively looked at as a group and
made sure we were all on the same page.
But it was um he's a guy that we think
can play inside, can play outside, you
know, has some has enough speed. um good
with contested catches. You saw some run
after catch uh with him. If you just
want to watch his highlight tape, go
watch the Syracuse game. Uh he, you
know, they just kept throwing him the
ball and uh but we we like what he it's
competition. You know, a lot of these
moves, you know, that we'll continue to
talk about, you know, that that happened
the rest of the day are just trying to
add more depth and more competition,
which I kind of referenced last night.
>> What What did you like about Bel?
>> Yeah. No, I mean all the the same type
of things, the versatility, you know,
you I always talk about having having
guys that can play outside, play inside.
You know, you see they ask them to do a
lot of different things. Um, you see him
make the contested catches down the
field. You see him take a, you know,
take a screen behind the line of
scrimmage, you know, and um, do a lot of
good things with it. Um, you know, I
think he has a he has a unique skill set
and, um, those are the type of guys that
sometimes you don't think are going to
be there and then they're they they're
there and you're you got to take
advantage of that. that part right
there. Were you surprised that he was
there in the fourth round because his
production and then his testing and he
was a name that seemed to be generating
a lot of buzz leading up to this week?
>> Yeah, I mean we he was, you know, as we
were strolling down last night looking
at names, you're like, you know, who are
the guys that we'll be talking about at
101? And and I would say there was
several guys we were talking about and
you know him being one of them and and
you take Jude well we moved back to 102.
Take Jude and you know as it got close
and he's sitting there it was sometimes
when guys get on the clock you're like
all right do we want the corner? Do we
want the you know the O lineman here?
This one. We kind of knew you know this
was this was who it was going to be. We
It's funny we talk about we don't we
don't say the names because every time
we say them or talk about them they get
drafted.
>> Happened again today
a lot today. But can you talk about how
you stole Jaylen Kil?
>> Yeah. Uh Jaylen was another guy we
really liked. Um and we had a pretty
good value. We sent Joe Dana um down to
work him out. Spent some time with him.
Very familiar with that program. Know
Shane Beamer very well. actually called
Shane again this morning uh on my way in
and just wanted to run through him one
more time and you know he's a he was
going back through some stuff that I
didn't even remember maybe I'd heard
before but played a high school where he
played you know he was the best player
on the team played quarterback punt
return like he was just get the ball in
his hands did some punt return there he
mentioned that he had a muff or two but
he said in fairness to him he wasn't the
main guy we just sometimes as a throw
him back there. We probably didn't give
him the reps. So, we'll that's something
else that that we would potentially look
at for him, but he's a safety first.
Played kind of a hybrid star nickel
position there. Their plan if he came
back was to move him to safety and
that's why we sent Joe Dana down just to
do the safety stuff, talk to him, and
that's where he'll transition to.
>> Brandon, as you talked about yesterday,
um there's probably more
openings on the roster on the defensive
and and and does what this reflects is
this a fair reflection of what what what
you what you like as far as six
defensive players and you know you've
got a punter position there too.
>> Yeah, I mean Jim Leonard told us he
wasn't going to take the job for Joe if
we didn't promise him you know more than
five draft picks so he's still here.
That was why we did all the trades.
>> We didn't want to lose Jim. But uh no,
in all seriousness we we thought we
needed kind of like last year more
youth. Uh we look for some some speed,
some size, like just some versatility.
Uh just an infusion of some youth on the
defensive side of the ball. Uh was
something that as after we got through
free agency, we kind of turned our
direction to what what the draft looks
like, what we've already attained in
free agency or or resigned on our team.
And we felt like there was more
opportunities to compete at either
starting roles or key backups on the
defensive side of the ball. And we also
felt like there was enough depth in some
of some of those positions in the draft.
You know, we talked about it last night,
linebacker. We had not it was one we
were, you know, I mentioned tackle. We
were definitely looking at linebacker
yesterday. Two, it just didn't fall the
way our board, you know, fell yesterday
with with the two picks we made. And and
just with just as a followup,
>> how much if you reflect back to the DJ
Moore trade, how much did that open up
this draft where you didn't have to, you
know, you had that one thing locked in?
>> Yeah, I mean, I think we looked at this
draft and knew where we would be
selecting and we just, you know, that's
one of the things Joe and I talked about
was let's talk about some of these
players. he was still familiarizing
himself with the draft, but I kind of
went through where we're picking, you
know, we're probably not going to get a
guy of DJ's caliber. And so, let's make
this this 25 swap. And, you know, we'll
we'll see how the draft falls. We would
have, as I mentioned, we would have
taken a player at 26,
you know, if we were like, man, I can't
believe this guy's here. But we also
were like, if that's not the case, let's
see what ammunition we can get so that
we can fill some of these these holes
that that we were able to do yesterday
and today.
>> So, you've been pretty firm that you
like what you have on the interior D
line can play the nose and maybe we're
also wondering still what the defense is
going to look like too. We're not really
sure. Um, is this also a because it
looks like Zayn's a guy that potent a
true nose. Is this an endorsement on the
guys you have also still to firm that
you have what you like in the interior
line?
>> Yeah, I would say we do. I mean, I let
Joe talk about that, too, but I think um
you know, let's don't forget we missed
Dwayne Carter last year. He he's coming
back. Um you'll when you see him, he's
beefed up, you know, kind of up top. And
uh L, you know, Landon Jackson, you
know, as I I think I stated here before,
probably be more of that for eye roll
for us. He's our weight programs helped
him. You know, he really in fairness to,
you know, credit to him and to, you
know, Will and the strength staff, those
two guys have really added some some
good bulk and strength for the positions
that that we're going to ask them to
play in this defense. So, uh, excited
about them. I don't know if you want to
add anything, Joe.
>> Yeah, I mean, when you you look at our
defensive line right now, like, you
know, there there has been a lot of
investment in, you know, in draft
capital in the last couple years, right?
You talk about Dwayne Carter in the
third, Landon in the third, TJ last
year, you know, uh, you know, Dion, you
know, then you get you get here this
year, you know, we able to get Zayn,
like there's a lot of youth in there and
you can never have enough D linemen,
right? Whether it's outside outside
linebackers inside, right? you look at
um you know the waves that teams are
going against speaking from a guy
calling plays you know it's always good
when you see the second line you know
defensive line coming in and you know I
think the the best teams you go against
right there's there's not a huge drop
off you know when the when the second
line's coming in right and um so I think
that that's important um you know that
we're always you know continuing to have
the competition but also making sure
that we you know we're we're deep in
that in those rooms and you know I think
Brandon you know has done a great job
you know kind of put that together.
>> Brandon Elarm was Elarmzor
isn't much bigger than than Dorian, a
little bit bigger than Terrell. A lot of
us thought you were going to get bigger
linebacker in this defense, but he
really doesn't bring much more size. Is
that just a thing you're looking for?
You don't want a big thumper. You'd
rather have a guy who's maybe a little
smaller and athletic. I don't know. What
is there a protoype for you guys?
>> Yeah, I mean, we want big, tall, long,
strong, fast. We do. Um, but they still
got to be good football players. So,
we're evaluating that. But, yeah, we
if you're an undersized player,
linebacker, you could say it for some
others positions, too. You got to make
up for it in other ways. Instincts,
quicks, speed like Terrell Bernard or or
Dorian or some of these guys do. I think
if Elum's aura was was bigger, like
you're saying, he's probably not hanging
around where we took him in the draft.
You know what I mean? Does that make
sense? So, um, yes, we there were guys
we valued a little higher in the draft
that were but it just didn't didn't fall
that way, but we brought him in on a 30
visit. Really liked who he was. Think
he's an arrow up player. He'll get he'll
get stronger here, but yeah, I mean, at
the end of the day, don't just chase,
you know, the card, you know, which is
the measurables. make sure you're still
getting a good football player and and
we like what he'll bring. Think he'll be
a good fourth down player too, you know,
for Jeff Rogers.
>> So, what was it like the first draft as
a head coach and you know, a lot of
trades, so I'm quite sure, you know, you
got a lot of lot of experience when it
comes to making those trades. So, how
was it for you?
>> No, look, it was it was good. You you
you know, when I we talked earlier, you
know, uh earlier in the week when we
were just going through just the basics
of like some of the mocks, right? like
um you really never know. It's like, oh,
cool. Let's, you know, are we let's
trade back here. What is this going to
well if when you actually do it, you
know, and to have a plan and to like
stick with it and talk about like, hey,
this is the this is the core. This is
where we'd like the range we'd like to
pick. We think we can get these guys in
this range to actually it's one thing to
say it, but then, you know, just seeing
them kind of kind of go through it in
the first round. I mean, to go from what
was it? 26 to 28 to 31. I mean, that's
non-stop, you know, going through and
having to be ready to go and and making
sure you're getting enough value with
it. So, um, you know, it was it was a
unique experience for me just kind of
sit back and kind of taking it all in
and, um, you know, with the vision for
what we were looking for didn't change,
right? And we were able to, man, we
improved our roster right now. And I
mean, you look at the the names that we
were able to get, um, you know, it it
excites you, right? And so, um, you
know, as a as a head coach on these type
of days, right, you just kind of sit
back and watch watch the GMs kind of do
their things and you have a lot of
communication, but you know, it's it's
his game day and, uh, man, you got you
can't you can't help but be excited
about what we've kind of done.
>> What was your biggest surprise? Was
there maybe a player that you didn't
think was realistic that maybe fell to
you or it doesn't even have to be your
team specific, maybe a position that
went way earlier than you were
anticipating?
There's I mean there's always surprises
without you know naming names. I would
say you know we got one or two today
that I would say we had rated a little
bit higher at least around higher on our
board. Everyone values players for their
team for their fit for their you know
and again it that's where you do stack
your board a little bit by by need. If
you're like, man, I like this player,
but I'm not sure I'm going to get this
value out of him because I'm already got
some pieces in front of him, you may
slide him down a little bit. Um, but you
know, I think like anything, it's it's
funny when a couple positions go. We
took Jude and then some tackles started
going. You know, yesterday I got antsy
to go get IGB.
Well, I was going to try to be patient,
but I saw corners going. And I honestly,
as we started this draft, felt that was
the biggest hole in our roster was
corner. Um, and we talked about
yesterday why. And just the targets that
get put on their backs if you don't have
good enough players out there on the
perimeter.
>> With Torono, he obviously has speed. How
does that translate to the field and
what are you thinking you'll get out of
him?
>> Yeah, another 30 visit guy. Really
enjoyed getting to know him. uh
undersized uh feisty, tough, fast. You
see, you see his speed. He tested, you
know, even better than maybe what I saw,
but I still saw a guy with good play
speed. Uh versatility. I think you he's
played more outside at Missou, but I
think he could, you know, flex to to be
give us again a game if, you know, if
he's on our game day roster, the
flexibility to be a backup nickel. Uh I
think he can do some jobs for Jeff
Rogers as well on fourth down. So, um,
we liked the value there. He'll have to,
you know, come in here and and earn it.
>> Bel didn't play much special teams if if
any in college, but where he kind of
projects on the depth chart at this
moment, that would seem to be almost the
requirement of the of the job. So, how
do you evaluate whether a guy can do it
if you haven't seen it?
>> Great question. Uh, we talk about that
all the time. And uh sometimes there's a
mix of opinion of well, you know, he's
got he beat that press, but that's not
double vice. You know what I mean? That
as a if he was going to be a gunner for
us or or whatever jobs you're going to
ask him to do. I think what you're doing
is you're you're trying to project and
you're what's the DNA? You know, you got
to be a dog out there. I think he is a
tough dude. I think you see that in his
play. Um, is he a willing blocker? You
know, to me, he's going to have to come
in here and earn his role. Uh, we do
think he's a smart player. And so, the
best way for him to get on the field
this year for us and for Joe and Pete is
to be able to play multiple spots, which
physically he can do. You've got to
mentally do that. Um, can he be a force
in the run game, too? you know, we we
put, you know, whatever that saying is,
uh, no block, no rock, or however you
want, you know, whatever. Joe's probably
got a better saying than that. But, um,
whatever you say, we do think he has the
DNA to do that. Some of these guys in
college are not necessarily asked, as
you said, to do it, but that's something
we'll tell them. Hey, man, like, yeah,
we want you to be a good receiver, but
it could come down to whether you get a
jersey, what's your what's your other
jobs here? just make sure you have
enough or you could find yourself
inactive until you kind of get that
figured out.
>> Joe, how do you think this reflects your
anticipate a fullback on the roster?
>> Uh, look, I think we're always always
evaluating a lot of stuff. I mean, look,
you looked, you can see, you know, you
kind of go back to Matt's question. You
can just see look how many tight ends
went yet yesterday. I mean, there's two
fullbacks went today or two or three
fullbacks. Like, you kind of you look at
the draft and you kind of see the
direction of maybe the league's, you
know, kind of going. Like I bet Jackson
alls in this year's draft would probably
been a pick yesterday and we were able
to get him late five, right? Um, you
know, so it's it's unique from that
perspective. Um, yeah, you know, I think
we're, you know, just because of the
drafts over that doesn't mean we're not,
you know, Bean's not always continuing
to look at the roster and trying to find
the competition, find figuring out ways
to to kind of go about it. You know, I
don't think we necessarily have to have
a fullback.
>> Do you think can Jackson play like an
Hback type of role a little bit?
>> Yeah, I mean, you can Yeah, we have we
have such a unique tight end room that
you can do a lot of different things
with those guys, right? And so, um, you
know, that's part of our job as coaches
is to, you know, figure out what those,
you know, what type of skill sets and
the type of run schemes that you can
kind of get creative with, you know,
without that stuff. Um, you know, but,
uh, like I said, there's there's plenty
of time for us to kind of figure that
out.
>> Joe, you talked about wanting the
defense to kind of adapt, adopt the
attacking style that the offense has
had. Now that you've seen, and you
haven't practiced yet, now that you've
seen who the players are who are going
to make up most of your team, how do you
think just now maybe fits your vision?
>> Yeah. No, I think um like we're we were
intentional about some of the guys that
we brought in um uh the edge that we
want to play with, right? We we we've
talked to, you know, going back to the
combine, right? Like um in order to be
able to rush the pass, you have to stop
the run first, too, right? And so, you
know, a conscious thing of of making
sure that we're, you know, put together
a scheme and have guys that have the
personality, understanding the dirty
work that comes with being able to then
get to the point that we can rush the
passer, getting to the point that we can
be able to defend the pass, you know, in
third and long situations, right? And
so, um, you know, I'm I'm excited about,
you know, going back to just TJ Parker
right from the jump, right? And so, um,
that has to excite you. Um, you know,
uh, we were we were glad to get him
where we got him. And so, um, you know,
those are the type of guys that kind of
help, you know, put together your
through your identity and the vision
that you have for what you want this
defense to look like.
>> Coach, when you I mean, during the oral
interview process, when you spoke to the
guys, I heard physicality, violence,
nastiness, how does that make you feel
as a coach when you hear your rookies
mimic those type of things?
>> Yeah, I mean, the football is not a uh
it's not a it's not a a kind sport. It's
not a fair sport, right? Like, you got
to you got to be able to bring it. We we
talk about the competitive stamina. Like
I want guys that I told the guys on the
team the other day like we're going to
draft guys on on the team that from your
position good, you know, like it's going
to elevate everybody. Um, right. We want
we want guys that are going to compete.
Like I want to go out to practice and
OTAAS and training camp and it's guys
fighting for jobs and it's only going to
make our team better. And you know,
that's what's so cool about looking
about looking at our draft right now is
the competition, you know, on our team.
And sometimes it it can kind of get, you
know, thrown out there as like we're
just building for depth. We're not
building for depth. We're we're
improving our depth and we're improving
the guys at the jump because I think
it's a it's a mindset of guys. If we got
the right guys in the room that I do
think we have when you draft someone
from your room, it's only going to
elevate your play. Um and so that
physicality, the mindset, the
personality that you know that these
guys kind of have, there's a reason
we're bringing them in here. And you
know, uh they're going to have to go
earn it. You know that none of these
guys are just going to be given
anything, but it's going to um them
going to earn is only going to improve
whoever else is in the room as well.
>> Brandon, you went through a couple
punters last year. What What made you
want to give one during this draft and
what was the process that you guys went
through to evaluate that led you to
find?
>> Yeah, I mean you're going to you're
going to lean on coach Rogers and his
experience. You know, he he really spent
a lot of time following these guys. I
mean, our scouts did as well. Got them
on the radars and then uh of the
coaches, him and Turner West, and they
really kind of gave us their thoughts.
We, you know, we had the scouting
thoughts, they had theirs, and and he
was a guy, like anything, we we had some
guys up there earlier, maybe even had a
couple others that we pulled off, but we
kind of talked through
hang direction, touch toe, all that
stuff like this guy's really good, but
I'm worried about him getting him
blocked. Uh, this guy I'm worried, you
know, kicks line, he kicks him long, but
I'm worried about line drive. So, we
went through all that. Uh, but
definitely a lean to coach Rogers and
his experience in the league. And so
Tommy was a guy that we had on our draft
board. And you know, as Joe just said,
we're we're looking for depth and
competition everywhere. It doesn't
matter if it's a kicker, a punter, a
long snapper, quarterback, whatever it
is, where can we add that? And, you
know, iron sharpens iron. And Mitch is a
proven guy here. This is by no means
going to be a job like any of these
other guys drafted handed to him. You
know, you're only going to keep one
punter. Uh but, you know, we're not
worried about if if a seventh round, you
know what I mean? It it was just at that
point in the draft, it made sense. Uh we
wanted to go to camp with two punters.
That's our plan. Two punters, two
kickers. And uh at this point in the
draft, that was one of the reasons
despite S's disdain that we traded back
to not have to fight for a punter post
draft.
>> Yeah. But then we couldn't have got
>> We also couldn't have got the guard in
the corner, right? Like
>> he's versatile.
>> Yeah. Yeah. No, I would have had to
fight for him. S
>> with Durant. Um he seems to have a
similar body type and skill set to Ed to
some degree. Um I know Ed's been nicked
up the last couple years. Was that kind
of a similar skill set you were looking
for just to have as a rotational piece
behind Ed or
>> He was a player that we valued on our
board. We went through it and we weren't
necessarily
like we said with linebacker or some of
these other piece. We got to try and hit
this in the draft uh at some point. Uh
but you know to Boy's question earlier
like what he was sticking out on our
board and we just said you know what you
and Joe said like this guy's inside rush
like let's just you know don't be afraid
I know we have some depth there but
let's if he's still sticking there
without saying his name because we
didn't want to jinx it. But um I think
we were calling him Penn State. Yeah.
But
>> I learned a lot this draft.
>> Yeah. Joe said a name and it went and I
was like
>> Yeah. I was like, "Oh, ah, okay. Got it.
Got it."
>> Usually somebody just says a name and
then there it goes and it Joe was
showing me a text and had the name on it
and the guy went
>> the fact that um back to Tommy the fact
that he hunted at Michigan for four
years outside Northern School and the
fact that he has been a kickoff
specialist.
>> Did that tilt anything for him?
>> Yeah, I mean that added value,
versatility. the more you can do. Um we
saw last year um Mitch had to kick off
for us um when we were dealing you know
with an injury. So um
>> and especially I'm sorry with the way
that with with Tyler recovering from the
injury, is that something you would
think about even more?
>> Yeah, I mean listen you you you would
love for those guys to all you like for
your punter in a pinch to be able to
kick field goals. You'd like for T Bass
in a pinch to be able to kick punts.
Anything can happen at least to get you
out of a game. Um, so yeah, that's
that's another reason the more things
you can do that separates yourself from
being an undrafted punter, you know, in
this case to a guy that's on your board
that you're willing to, you know, put a
pick in.
>> What do you what have you seen from TJ
Sanders this this off season? And for
both of you, what's the plan for him and
how excited are you for him in his
second season?
>> Yeah, it was kind of like uh, you know,
when we did the the question, you know,
uh, media the other day, right? It's
it's so early, right? Like I you I'm not
even allowed to be in the weight room
with these guys. We were able to do some
of the you know, the mini camp the other
day, but you know, in the we start phase
two to on Monday, whatever today is,
right? So, um the only the only
interactions we can have right now were
hey, we're we're meeting with guys,
right? And so, um but TJ's TJ's hand
doing everything the right way right
now. Um look, he was second round draft
pick last year, right? There's a um a
clear vision for how to utilize him,
understanding what he does well. um Jim
and the defense coaches are excited for
him and just like everybody's usually
you're going to improve your second year
and have an idea of understanding what
it takes to be a pro and all of that.
And so I'm excited for uh for TJ and um
you know going into this draft like you
know you got TJ in the second round last
year like it's going to be an excitement
to be able to keep him in the rotation.
>> A lot of the selections today were
highend testing guys athletically. How
much was that something you looked at
when you were adding?
>> You You always love it when when that
works out. Some years it doesn't. I feel
like it's come up, man. You didn't, you
know, you didn't have great testers or
you didn't have great measurables. Um,
but it I think this year it kind of
turned up that way. It wasn't like an
overemphasis from our new coaches or,
you know, we didn't we didn't change
anything, but you love when the football
player matches the testing. And so, we
love good testers, but we always do want
to make sure they still check, you know,
check all the boxes required for their
position as a as a player, at least at
least above the line.
I know every draft is different, but as
you reflect on other drafts, what stuck
out as unique about the 2026 draft? Uh
well, we probably Thursday night like
just,
you know, knowing that if we made the
pick at 26,
which we would have, you know, but we
talked about, man, we better really like
this player because it's going to be a
long wait till 91 and there's going to
be some players that we have to watch go
to other teams. So, I think that's the
part that I'm excited about that that
all played out the way it did. Uh, it
doesn't always happen. You got to have,
you know, just like I talked about the
trade deadline, you got to have a
partner. There's been times you want to
trade and you just can't you can't make
it work or you can't find someone
willing to to come up. But we had the
good fortune to do that three times and
then end up with a player that we really
coveted in in TJ at a similar value that
of what we you know he would have been
in the conversation as I said yesterday
at 26 for us. So to do that and end up
with the names that we did we're
excited. I mean these guys are going to
have to come and improve themselves. Um
but without going from 26 to 91, how we
were able to change that and get a
player at 60 whatever we took um 62 for
IGB. Um and then having the first pick
today, we had a lot of action for that.
We could have traded back further, but
as I mentioned, we were like glad we
didn't because we saw the run on
tackles, you know, before our next
fourth round pick. So that's why we just
did the deal with the Raiders to add
something and we had an inkling what
they were going to do.
>> Throughout the last few months of draft
process, have you learned anything new
about Joe?
>> About Joe? Joe is uh Joe's very patient.
Um he remembers things way better than
than I do. Like he you know he just got
thrown into the draft process. you know,
he hired a coaching staff and, you know,
was really starting to learn these guys
in in Indie for the combine and then we
go to free agency. Like, he remembers
way more than you would think somebody
would who's trying to bring his staff
on, get himself ready for his first year
of coaching. And, you know, even, you
know, it's got to be frustrating because
it's sometimes, you know, as coaches,
you're going to look at, man, I might
rather have this guy or this guy. You
got to make you got to make a choice.
And sometimes this with scouts too.
They're like I can feel him behind me
going or like and I think Joe's patience
is um that's one of his great leadership
traits that's that's going to be good
for our team. He was he was awesome
throughout the process and even you know
listen there's there's a player or two
that you always relive back probably
like him as a play caller that I'm like
damn if I knew it was going to go that
way I would have I would have done that.
You just don't know. You just don't know
sometimes and you're trying to play the
board. You're trying to project when
there's going to be a run, when your
next pick is, and like any I'm excited
about these guys and we got some good
players, but you always think about,
damn, could I have gotten this guy and
still got that player at a position that
we didn't end up with today. So, um, but
Joe was for his first, you know, time
through there was he had way more
patience than I would have if the role
was flipped. How do you feel about the
collection of talent offensively? Not a
ton of changes, but those you have made.
>> Yeah. No, I like
you know when you when you uh when you
start the offseason with the trade for
DJ, right? Like you know it was we were
sitting there and I know we ended up
getting second two second round picks,
right? But it was like, hey man, that
second round might be a while, but the
whole time it's like, hey, don't forget
we, you know, we got we got DJ Moore,
right? And so I thought that that was uh
that was really important and you know
being able to pick up Jude and and and
Bell and and these guys like uh yeah we
have a very competitive offense we we
had last year but you know we had to
find ways to get better and we have to
get better right and um you know we I
felt like we improved our receiver core.
We were going to bring in offensive
linemen and so um I think that's only
going to help our team and you know um
going against the defense that we're
going to be getting going against the
different type of schemes and stuff
that's that's only going to improve us
as well. So, um, a lot of football, a
lot of a long time until we get to see
what we're made of, but I really like
what we're building.
>> Brandon, this year and last year, you've
used your top 100 picks, all on defense.
I think that's five in total.
>> Do you feel like with the scheme change
and Jim taking over that that created
defensive needs that maybe otherwise
wouldn't have been there this this year?
>> I really don't. I think just, you know,
sometimes your your roster goes through
various transitions due to age,
contract,
um, and there's a little bit of a
transition here, maybe a player or two,
but in reality,
the cool thing, I think I've told you
guys when Jim came in and talked to our
scouts that day for an hour and whatever
he did, he was like, "Don't just chase
play like bring me good football
players. We'll we'll make it work. this
all this doesn't have to be a one-year
flip it all around like that's that's
their job and that's refreshing because
it takes a little bit of like angst of
holy cow if I don't get this done in
free agency or the draft I'm kind of
setting this team up for failure and um
but no I think part of it is just we did
truly no matter who's you know what type
of system we're running or who's
coaching the team we did need some
infusion of youth
on this on this defense and I just think
it's more where the iteration of this
roster is more than a a coaching
transition.
>> Brandon, you brought it up a few times
that you felt like you had to add
quarterback.
Is it more than just is there more to it
than that? Because you mentioned dep
layer to it. Yeah, I mean listen I think
you know you you sometimes go into the
year you know last year we started with
and maybe it's a scar from from last
year or a previous year more in the
playoffs but I just our depth's really
been tested there for a variety of
reasons and you always learn as you go
through and listen you can still only
keep so many at the 53 you can only put
so so much talent on the practice squad
But, um, you know, we were at training
camp last year and, you know, we had
Trey back, CB, we just drafted Max, we
drafted Dorian Strong, um, Jammarcus
Ingram, Dane Jackson was back after a
free agent stent in Carolina and was
looking at the depth and we were like,
man, this this might be our our deepest
collection of corners. And then you go
through the season of what happened to
us and you get in the playoffs in in the
big games, you know, it's a passing
league and you're going to face the top
quarterbacks, the top play callers. And
those guys on an island get tested and
so I, you know, I was, as I said, I
truly felt like we needed to get better
there. We looked in free agency, but
it's a premium position and we spent our
dollars on DJ Moore and and Chub and
getting Conor McGovern and some of the
other pieces back. We did get deoffered
uh which which was a guy we are very
excited about. But I think that's really
it. It's just you live and you learn.
And like I said, it could be another
position in the future, but you know,
it's happened a couple of times to us.
And so just trying to make sure we're
deep enough, not only for the season,
but that we're walking into the
postseason playing with our best
players.
>> I know you said um just for roster
purposes, Landon more before I Javon,
you said the other day would be more of
a stand up outside linebacker. Where do
you see Andre Jones in that group
fitting in? Um, probably I mean I think
he's versatile. I would say right now
probably more like a a rousoe kind of
standing up.
>> How many how many scenarios you gone
through before the draft actually
happened? How many of these scenarios
did you go through trading back the way
you did and how much did it really you
know come to true life? How much did
that come to?
>> Yeah, probably probably five or six
times went through it with with trade
scenarios in it. We went to we went to
26 twice and then we started going all
the way to 91 with trade scenarios. We
even went to 126 one time. That got a
little wacky. Uh so after doing that
once we didn't but it did kind of give
us an idea of where the depth of the
draft was even more and what players
were would be there and and I think it I
think parts of this thing did play out
you know that way on on Thursday night.
>> Brandon you mentioned Jay Valai
yesterday brought him up unprompted
today. Just for either of y'all what has
he meant to you guys during this
process? You want to talk about the most
positive guy in the building like
energy, you know, wears this medium
shirt, you know, the uh he's dude's cut,
man. Uh but he is uh I love his juice. I
love his energy. I could probably hand
him somebody like Boyco and he would
say, "I can I got this. I can turn him
into something."
And so, uh but
we hope we don't get there. We just we
just talked through that.
>> We don't want that to
>> But I I I'm I'm impressed. Yeah. And we,
you know, very little on the field so
far because we just started, but I've
talked to Max and CB and these guys and
u I think they feel his juice and his
energy and um it's been refreshing to
see.
>> I know we talked a ton about a Benos
yesterday, just the ideology around the
pick. That was probably about his in
your entire tenure the most shocking
pick. just reading the fan base.
>> But I think sometimes there's a
disconnect between whether it be your
board, the inside football evaluations
and like the public draft Twitter, draft
online is so big. What's your sense on
the value you got in him specifically in
that trade out there?
Well, the value we got in here him is,
as I said, you could start to see the
run on corners and he, you know, we had
him in a in in a spot on our board that
we're like, all right, there's going to
be another little drop if if you don't
get him. If you got two or three sitting
right with him, maybe you're a little
you're a little more patient. But, um, I
also I think what he you got CB, you got
Max, two different guys, a bigger,
sturdier guy. uh not the same speed that
Max has in CB. We know what Max's skill
set is. We've talked about this. This is
a long press. Um get his hands on you. I
think we have three different skill sets
here. Um you know, and you hate to do
comparisons, but you know, it was said
to me and I'll say like back when we
evaluated Joey Porter Jr. a little bit
coming out like and again I'm not
putting him up there. Joey Porter Jun
Jr.'s been a great player in this
league. If if he turns out like that, we
nailed the pick. Um, but that play style
with that size and and length. And you
know, he's he's wired the right way.
He's got the right makeup. You guys will
see that as you as you get around him.
Uh, I'm I'm excited to get him. That's a
premium position that you can sit there
and say, "Hey, I'm gonna take him down
here because he had, you know, S
referenced the penalties last night from
a year ago." I would look at it that
the guy took it serious and he was
intentional about improving his game and
he cut it. I don't know, is it 15 to
four? Is that the number? Okay. I think
we we talked about on the stairs. if it
went from four to 15
the other way, we'd probably, you know,
be a little more concerned. So, uh, a
guy that will continue some a lot of
that's technique, things like that. And
Jay Valai will will work on that. But,
um, I think I think our fans will really
be glad we have him when they when they
see him as he learns and grows here.
>> On Q on my fullback question, there's a
report now fullback Jackson Aer will be
signing an undrafted free agent deal
with the Bills. Is that right? Is that a
guy? Can we confirm that or not?
>> Who broke it?
>> Uh Aaron Wilson.
>> Okay. I don't know. Yeah. Uh yeah, I
think it's uh the guys were working on
that as as we came down. Um but
>> got it done, right?
>> Yeah.
>> Thanks, Joe. Heard you say that. I
better go there.
>> Yeah.
>> Okay. So, what was the goal with this
draft plan before we let you guys go?
>> The defining goal get better, improve
depth, competition.
Thanks guys.
>> Derek, we'll see you on the field.